.:: YIFYMOVIES.IS ::.
Watch YIFY Movies Online For Free
Today, March 11th...
I received the tragic news
of an unprecedented earthquake
of magnitude 9,
and the destruction
caused by the tsunami.
The number of victims
is growing steadily
and the extent of the damage
caused by this disaster
is impossible
to assess at this moment.
Foreign volunteers are joining
OUT massive FGSCUG GffOTtS.
We will overcome this setback...
--rebuild the ravaged areas,
and Japan itself.
Join me in praying
for our success.
Total number of casualties?
Roughly?
Nearly 8000 in our area.
It's a rotten situation.
Could blow at any time.
I can't use any machines.
It's all hanging
by a thread.
Twenty-eight people
were taken out alive.
They say there are five more
in the dining hall.
Two girls, three guys.
All Germans.
They're in there.
It rained and the mud
sealed it tight.
We cleaned it up
and put in a tube with a camera.
We'll try from
the other side too.
That's all we can do
right now.
None of them
are hurt badly. But they're lying
only 30 centimeters below the slab.
Very dangerous.
It could go again at any moment.
Keep calm, kids.
This is the doctor speaking.
Don't all talk at once.
There isn't much oxygen.
Just one of you.
Answer after I've asked a question.
Briefly describe things for me.
Who is this?
This is Nina.
Can you hear me?
There are five of us.
We're all-- We're all still alive.
Very good, kids.
Here's how we're going to do this:
Stay still and try to conserve oxygen.
After we get you out,
we can talk in more detail.
No. Please don't go.
Just talk to us a little, okay? Please.
I can't go. The subway is closed.
Does anyone know you're here?
Your mother? Father?
Yes. My mother knows.
My father is dead.
[SOBBING]
I miss him so much.
Hey, Nina. Nina, don't cry.
You'll use up all the oxygen.
I had five fathers,
and I miss them all.
They're all dead. But I'm not crying.
Five fathers?
That's not possible.
Possible, impossible.
How would you know?
It is possible.
Stalingrad
My God.
Walking on water?
Yeah. We're all apostles now.
Shush, you little shit.
Barely out of diapers
and you make jokes.
I'll give you a whipping.
That's enough, Pop.
The sappers swamped the crossing
so you can't see it from above.
God help them then.
Let's go, brothers.
It was in Stalingrad.
Autumn, 1942.
The Russians were crossing
the Volga
to gain a foothold
on the other bank
and keep the Germans
from taking the city
and the river access.
This was all but impossible.
But they didn't think about that.
Each one fought his best,
not knowing that he was fighting
in the bloodiest battle
in human history.
Not good.
Scouts.
Jump.
Pouch, helmet.
Okay, jump-
Sit down.
Did you mark
the ways through?
Any mines?
Have you tried talking?
Chvanov.
At our factory
we had a deaf mute,
a retard.
There are no retards
in the USSR.
There are mentally ill,
but no retards.
Okay. Wait for
the assault group,
lead them to the oil tanks,
then catch up.
Let's go.
We're here. The building is here.
We sneak in. Then it's a coin flip,
heads or tails.
Heads, we look for the detonator.
Should be on the second floor.
No reason for them
to put it any higher
where it could get hit.
Tails, we find
the detonator right away
and kill them all.
We cut every wire we find.
That's it.
Jilrgens. JUrgens.
The Russians are coming.
[IN GERMAN] What?
Radio the news.
There's no signal, captain.
All right, JUrgens.
I'd rather not ask
why there's no signal.
Blow up the tanks.
But that's the fuel
for the whole army, captain.
Jilrgens.
You're an idiot.
The Russians are here.
[IN GERMAN]
I'll be back in a second.
[MAN 1 SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
IN GERMAN]
[IN GERMAN]
The Russians have trenches there.
Both flanks are mined.
We couldn't advance
due to heavy fire.
Grenades!
[SCREAMS]
[GUNFIRE]
[WHISPERS]
Found you, you son of a bitch.
[GRUNTING]
[SHOUTS IN GERMAN]
[MAN 3 SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
Well, God save us. Let's go, son.
My boy.
Stand guard.
I'll go upstairs.
Comrade. I'm one of you.
I'm a spotter.
Find my radio. I need it.
Comrade.
There it is.
We made it here yesterday
from the fire station.
The Germans killed my radioman.
Are you scouts?
Yeah. But what the hell
are you?
I told you, I'm a spotter.
An officer.
Officer?
I direct artillery.
Why'd the krauts hang you
like a Christmas ornament?
I haven't slept
for three days.
I was weak. I froze.
You fucked up
the crossing, asshole.
They burned alive.
There was no cover fire.
And you haven't slept?
Commander.
What is it?
Semyonov's dead.
Our radio's broken.
His works. Should we keep him?
You really know
how to use the radio?
Yes.
Contact headquarters.
I Will.
Give me the frequency
and your call sign.
It's Kaluga,
44 and three.
Sissy.
Don't call me "Sissy."
I'm an officer
of the worker-peasant army.
Give me a gun, please.
Contact HQ.
If you don't, I'll shoot you.
CHVANOV:
Captain! Come quick.
Who's he got?
Is it a boy?
Are you okay, kid? Shh.
It's a girl. Heh.
Definitely a girl, commander.
She's shell-shocked,
out of her mind.
We'll sort it out later.
And Nikiforov?
CHVANOV:
There he is.
He brought a grubby guest.
Who the devil are you?
I'm no devil, comrade captain.
I'm an angel.
Polyakov. Gun commander.
GROMOV: Gun commander?
POLYAKOV: Yes, sir.
And where's this gun
you command?
Over there, in the archway.
Got any shells?
POLYAKOV: Yes.
One round.
I see.
Well, then, let's do some fighting.
Comrade captain!
It's division HQ.
Sit down.
So we have to
babysit her now?
That's all we need, damn it.
Commander, look what
the krauts did to her.
It's a war, Angel. She's alive.
NARRATOR:
That's how they met.
Five men, charred by
two years of fighting,
blown by the wind from the big towns
and backwaters of our huge country
to a city spread along
the banks
of a great river.
Five men and my mother.
My young mother.
The building where Mama lived
blocked one of the exits to the Volga.
For months, our troops
would capture the building
and then leave again.
Mama was tired
of living in an inferno,
tired of being shocked
by human grief,
human cruelty
and even by her own patience.
Mama just kept living
in her old home
and didn't want to leave it.
This was her room, her apartment,
her stairs, her street,
and finally, her city.
She simply couldn't abandon it.
It was a few days
before her 19th birthday.
CHVANOV:
What have we here?
A fountain.
Three hundred meters.
Nobody runs
from Chvanov.
Nothing hides
There's a broken tank
in the shop window.
Goddamned krauts.
Their machines are garbage.
Nothing works.
Nothing shoots.
Mm...
They made a nest, the filthy birds.
GROMOV: Chvanov.
CHVANOV:
Mm?
Go down and see
how the guys are doing.
Okay. Sissy,
how did you do this?
NARRATOR".
In Apartment 8,
former home
of Sazonov, Mama's neighbor,
collector of butterflies and insects,
Gromov had set up his lookout point.
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
Hold the building for three days
until the division forces
cross to your side.
Understood?
GROMOV: Sort of, Number 4.
What don't you understand,
Number 2?
I don't understand
how to follow your order, Number 4.
You're regular army,
but you sound like a draftee.
You figure it out. Understood?
Yes, sir, Number 4.
That's all.
[TURNS OFF RADIO]
Stop.
What are you doing here?
Stop, stop.
Stop it. I won't hurt you.
You can't be here,
they'll kill you.
Get out.
This is my home, not yours.
Yours? Sure you don't mind us
barging in?
No. You can stay for now.
Give me your canteen.
That night, their ranks grew.
Every survivor nearby
came by instinct.
On the first ﬂoor there were sailors,
mobilized factory workers
and a few sappers.
They set up in Apartment 6
where the large Kulikov family
had lived.
Now there was a machine gun there.
[GUNSHOT]
The fascist bitch works.
Ha-ha-ha.
Come here.
Shoot some Germans with it.
I was joking.
Give me your canteens.
Will I get it back?
Here, here.
She's simple-minded.
You could do
whatever you want to her.
She's so small and sweet.
Can't you take a joke?
Don't just stand there.
What's the girl's name?
What's your name?
Katya.
Give me your canteen.
So,
comrade residents,
the first floor is yours.
Set it up and fortify it.
Stay inside.
Only shoot on command.
And get rid of the krauts.
They'll start to stink.
Pick them up
and toss them out.
GROMOV: Who's in charge?
I am.
Warrant Officer Krasnov.
And here?
Me. I'm the superintendent.
Hi.
Hello.
COLONEL [IN GERMAN]:
A soldier.
And another one.
There's an officer.
It's probably poor JUrgens.
What's wrong, Kahn?
Why haven't you made a report?
Your men get thrown out windows,
yet you're just fine.
Would you prefer me dead,
colonel?
I want to know why that
damn building is full of Russians.
My orders weren't to hold the site.
I was to blow up the fuel tanks
to keep them from the enemy.
Kahn, do you know
what distinguishes
a German officer
from other armies' officers?
Well?
He doesn't question orders,
he follows them.
That's precisely why
the Wehrmacht is at the Volga
and why it will soon
reach India. Don't worry.
I doubt you'll have to learn
how to ride an elephant.
Unh!
These goddamn lice.
Our men are scratching like monkeys.
The Russians put ash in their soap.
Ash?
In the soap?
Barbarians.
Kahn,
tomorrow, that whole damn
building will be ours.
You lost it to the Russians
and you're going to get it back.
Put ash in the soap
to kill the damn lice.
[IN GERMAN]
Yes, sir, colonel.
So they're throwing
our men out windows.
Then we'll have to
teach them a lesson.
CHVANOV:
Next.
An officer.
[SCOFFS]
Ooh.
Even a mangy sheep
has some wool.
ASTAKHOV: Freeze! Freeze!
WOMAN: Aah!
WOMAN:
Don't shoot!
We're on your side!
Hands up!
Put down the gun!
Hands UP!
WOMAN: My hands are full.
Who are you?
Locals.
You live here?
WOMAN:
No, near the port.
GROMOV:
Why are you here?
Check the baskets.
Give me that.
Dirt.
Definitely dirt. And sand.
We were at the river.
We always come this way.
Why?
We take dirt from the bank.
The Germans bombed
a grain barge.
We sift out the grain
to make porridge
for the children.
It's like chewing sand,
but you can still eat it.
Can we go?
The Germans.
And?
And what?
It's the front, stupid.
Your damned front
will move.
Then what, do we follow you?
We didn't let them take the city.
We live here.
We walk here every day.
Let her go.
I can't stand her voice.
I'll shoot you.
Shut up!
You shut up.
That's enough.
Lice?
Soap?
Yes, it's soap.
[CHATTERING]
MAN:
Don't look away,
you piece of trash.
Oh, God, he's back.
Haven't seen you for a week.
I was hoping you were dead.
[IN GERMAN]
Other people are eating
the food I bring you.
Are you giving it to them?
Or are they taking it from you, hm?
Look.
My wife.
The first time I saw you,
I could hardly believe the resemblance.
Don't you agree?
My Christina is dead.
Tuberculosis.
Who is that?
My wife.
Wife.
[SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN
THEN SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
[EXPLOSIONS]
I have to go.
The food is for you.
Do you understand? It's only for you.
I'll be back.
KAHN:
Listen up. If anyone takes food
from this woman,
I will personally shoot him.
GROMOV:
A gun, grenades.
One. Four more.
So...
listen.
Here's the city.
Here's the crossing.
This is our building.
If they take it,
they'll burn
the crossing again.
This is an ideal spot
so we can't let them in here.
Got it?
We don't have many rounds.
We have a German machine gun
with four belts.
Three.
GROMOV: Three.
Enough to fight for an hour.
There's the artillery.
The artillery's ready.
Okay, comrades.
You know your positions.
Man your posts.
They'll be here soon.
Wait a minute, captain.
We can go to our posts,
but what are we doing here?
Defending this building.
Those are our orders.
From who?
Division headquarters.
That's a different outfit.
You got the orders, so you follow them.
I'm going to go find
my own division. You stay here.
We're going back across.
Nikiforov, shoot the sailor.
SAILOR:
What?
Why'd you do that?
We could've used him.
What for?
I don't have a ship.
Commander.
On the square.
What's this circus?
Colonel, we've rounded up
the people.
Ask her if she's a Jew.
[IN RUSSIAN]
Are you a Jew?
A Jew? Not in my family.
We never even lived near any.
[GASPS THEN
SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[GIRL SCREAMING]
WOMAN 1: Let go!
WOMAN 2: Auntie Rimma!
Let them go!
Come on, come on.
Me and my little girl!
We're not Jews!
CHVANOV:
They're in the bus.
They're going to burn it, captain.
WOMAN 1:
Let the little girl go!
She's not a Jew, she's a child!
[WOMAN 1
SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
GRAMOV: See the officer?
CHVANOV: Yeah.
GRAMOV:
Can you get him?
How? The bastards
are hiding behind kids.
What in God's name
is going on?
Why weren't we ordered
to attack?
Kahn, I'll answer your question,
though I'm not required to.
I know the rules, colonel.
I have no doubt.
But in war, we'd all do well
to remember our roots,
our customs.
Our ancestors offered sacrifices
before battle.
Go back to your men.
The order to attack will come.
Or do you want to
watch the sacrifice?
No.
It's okay. It'll be okay.
Don't be afraid.
Someone will help us.
There you are.
KATYA: Don't just sit there!
Do something!
It's a woman with a child!
Shoot them!
They'll burn them alive!
It'll hurt!
Commander, calm her down.
She's right, Chvanov.
Shoot.
Shoot at children?
[GIRL SCREAMING]
[WOMAN 1 and GIRL SCREAMING]
Damn it!
Give me that.
[SOBBING]
[GUNSHOT]
God have mercy.
Burn in hell, scum!
[SCREAMS]
Attack!
Kill the bastards!
[SCREAMING]
Kill them with whatever
you've got!
[SHOUTING]
[YELLING]
[YELLS]
[SCREAMS]
MAN [IN GERMAN]:
Mortars in position!
Fall back!
Mortars!
Should've drowned them.
They keep crawling out
like rats.
Hey, blondie.
Report to the commander.
It'll sting for a minute.
Does it hurt?
It's okay. It'll heal.
Sasha.
Alexander Nikiforov.
Yes, I know your name.
Before the war, Mama and I
used to go to your concerts.
I know all your songs and arias.
Mama loved you.
My sister too.
Your portraits hung on our wall.
CHVANOV:
Nikiforov.
The commander wants you.
Sasha.
Will you sing for me
sometime?
Sing? Him?
He only talks twice a year.
Is there something
I don't know?
Come here.
[CHVANOV LAUGHS]
Alexander Nikiforov. Tenor.
RAUGHS]
NIKIFOROV: Did you call me, captain?
Come here.
See the plane?
See it?
It's a Heinkel.
He was going to bomb
the crossing. Bastard.
There are two machine guns
and a smaller gun
in the radioman's cabin.
Nikiforov. Sappers, help him.
Take the rifle
and some tools.
Wrap them up
so they don't rattle.
I'm a sapper,
not a repairman.
Go on! Go!
[WHISPERS]
What's the matter?
We killed 14 Germans.
They got six of us.
We got off easy.
Got a smoke?
I'm off.
Go ahead.
NARRATOR".
By age 14,
Nikiforov had been picked up
10 times by the police.
But fate was to send him
to work in a tractor factory
where there was a House of Culture
that was famous
throughout Stalingrad.
By age 16, he had
an amazingly pure tenor voice.
The factory sent him to Moscow
to the conservatory.
A year before the war,
he returned to Stalingrad
as a soloist with the Philharmonic
and became a local celebrity.
On the first day of the war,
he signed up as a volunteer.
For 20 days, he was lost
in the human slaughterhouse
of the Belarusian forests
until he found his unit.
The Soviet military police
questioned him for 20 days more.
Those terrible first months of the war
made him stern, silent,
and even cruel.
Take a look at this filthy animal.
Peter Kahn.
Recipient of an Iron Cross.
Born to respected Prussian stock.
Field Marshal Paulus
invited me to lunch once.
He called me a hero.
A hero.
It's impossible to wage war
against you people.
You know nothing of honor.
You're all bandits,
who'd shoot someone in the back.
You're not fighting for victory,
you want revenge.
I came here
as a soldier.
You've turned me into a beast.
[PLAYING NOTES ON PIANO]
So, what do you say,
want a shooting lesson?
Don't want to anymore?
Why are you
shaking your head?
Speak up.
I still want to.
Want to.
Three, four, now she
wants you on the floor.
You were here
with the Germans...
but you don't talk about it.
That's not good.
Definitely not good.
Listen to that guy.
He doesn't talk, he spews.
He's got a dirty mouth.
Katya, don't listen to him.
What are you looking at'?
You want to know how we lived
under the Germans?
What they did to us?
Why I'm still alive?
And not with Mama and Papa
in a grave?
Why I didn't kill myself?
Go on, ask. Don't be shy.
Go ahead and ask.
Our defenders.
You want details?
I just couldn't do it.
I was scared.
I was waiting for you.
Shoot.
Go on, then.
What's the matter?
I'll kill him.
Sit down!
He said sit down.
Forget what you
just heard.
Polyakov, go calm her down.
[EXPLOSION IN DISTANCE]
POLYAKOV:
Mortars.
U?“
Some kind of artillery.
I have a beautiful wife.
I chose her from the village
for her beauty.
My village is far away,
near Bryansk.
We made a life.
We were haPPY-
I took care of her.
I bought her a kerchief,
some felt boots.
She liked me to stroke
herhead.
I'd come home
and sit by her,
she'd put her head
on my lap,
and I'd stroke it.
She had long,
black hair.
Just before New Year's
in '39,
we had a daughter.
I look like a grandpa, right?
[CHUCKLES]
But I had a baby daughter.
I'm sleepy-
May I?
Just a little nap.
I'm not heavy.
NARRATOR:
By then,
Vasiliy Polyakov's
wife and daughter
had been dead for almost a year.
They'd been living in Moscow
where Polyakov
had been given two rooms.
They died senselessly
during a bombing in October, 1941.
They didn't reach the shelter.
They had stopped to help a woman
whose baby carriage had fallen over.
She and her baby lived,
but they didn't.
Polyakov's wife
was 26 years younger than him.
He told all this to my mother,
who for him, on that night,
was the only person on earth.
You're a good girl, Katya. Pure.
Don't be afraid.
Masha, Masha, fascist tramp.
Off to wash?
You'll never get clean.
Go away.
Getting water?
Here's some water for you!
CHVANOV:
♪ Strike, my rifle ♪
♪ Quick and true ♪
♪ No mercy ♪
♪ For the foe ♪
♪ I'll help you with my sharp saber H'
What is it?
You said you'd
teach me to shoot.
[CHUCKLES]
Lie down, I'll teach you.
Butt on your shoulder,
your fingers go here.
I've seen you hold the rifle.
Teach me to use the sight.
Put your target
in the crosshairs and shoot.
KATYA:
Who's that?
CHVANOV:
Some woman.
She's pretty.
Yeah. I've seen her
a few times.
There's a kraut
who goes to that cellar.
Maybe to see her?
Shoot her.
Are you stupid?
[CHUCKLES]
A German.
CHVANOV:
You're right.
Lucky you. Found a German
on the first try.
Now look.
Look at his head
and chest,
head and chest.
KATYA:
He's thin. Glasses.
Walks like a goose.
Not too old.
Don't watch him,
watch where he goes.
Follow him.
Take him.
StOp!
U?“
You got him with
the first shot. Well done.
What was that, idiot?
What was what, commander?
You killed a soldier getting water.
A Nazi, not a soldier.
Even animals don't kill
at the waterside.
You know the saying,
captain?
"Kill him
each time you see him."
I don't give a damn
if he's drinking, eating
or shitting.
I killed him
and I'll keep on killing.
Mother said they killed my brother
because his name was
Vladimir llyich, just like Lenin.
The kid was 7 years old.
Do soldiers do that?
I'm the one who killed him.
Get out of my sight.
Misha Chvanov's mother
hadn't told him everything.
She couldn't. The SS
terrorized his village,
raped his beautiful older sister
and left her for dead
in the pigsty-
His mother was wounded.
Almost burned alive.
She joined the partisans.
They had to amputate
her wounded arm
due to gangrene.
Luckily she was left-handed
so Misha didn't notice any difference
in her handwriting.
There are times
you look like a normal woman
to me.
You could be German or French.
As if you wouldn't stab me in the back
as soon as I turned around.
But we both know the truth.
I don't understand a word.
Everyone out. You have five minutes.
Just grab what's important.
Well, this certainly is a sight.
A German soldier in his underpants
with a Russian whore
while the fuhrer's army
fights tooth and nail for the Volga.
Such exemplary camaraderie.
I'm speechless, captain.
Yes.
You've actually
rendered me speechless.
Do you have anything
to say for yourself?
Right.
I thought as much.
May I ask a question, sir?
You may not.
High Command has ordered us
to cleanse the combat zone.
So we're cleansing
the combat zone
of scum and filth.
Hm.
What do you think, Kahn?
Is she scum,
OI' filth?
Well,
I understand, you know.
You haven't captured
a Russian fortress,
but you did conquer a cottage.
You felt like celebrating.
As a man,
I can understand you.
But not as an officer.
Corporal.
Find a few women
to do laundry.
[IN GERMAN]
Yes, sir, colonel.
Take the old and ugly ones.
We have to get rid
of these damn lice somehow.
U?“
GROMOV:
Get up, go with Nikiforov.
I'm not going anywhere.
Leave.
Listen, you really
have to get out of here.
You're not good for the guys.
They're not fighting for their country
or Stalin. They fight for you.
That's bad.
Why?
Get dressed.
They can kill you, dummy.
They can't kill the motherland.
But you, there's no way
we can defend you.
If they kill you, the guys will fall apart.
Are you fighting for me too?
I won't fall apart.
I want to fight with you.
To kill Germans. To shoot them.
Listen, children under 16...
MY Passport.
You're right.
Today's the 15th.
So it's your birthday?
I'm 18, old enough to fight.
Nineteen today.
Happy birthday.
I'll go tell the others.
So...
Leave her alone,
captain.
Got it?
Yeah, I got it.
Stand up.
Quiet, quiet. You hear me?
Quiet, I said.
Listen to me, Sissy.
It's no good.
Hear me? No good.
She's not your woman,
got it?
Do you understand?
At ease.
U?“
Bastards are dug in behind the store.
They'll bomb the crossing.
Can't hit them from here.
Sissy.
Can you get your boys
from across the river
to hit them?
Too dangerous.
They'd hit us too.
Into the water!
Charge!
I'll take them out myself
with the cannon.
Cannons don't shoot
around corners.
They do for me.
Where are you taking them?
To the station, captain.
Why?
To load them on trains.
Masha!
Working with Germany,
you'll make a happy future
for yourselves.
Captain, this vehicle
belongs to the army post.
It belongs to the Wehrmacht, idiot.
Masha Mashed.!
Get on!
Get on.
Masha, get on.
Quiet, Chvanov.
Lieutenant Astakhov's smart.
He went to an academy.
Not like you, hayseed.
Village idiot.
An academy is one thing,
shooting around corners
is another.
GROMOV:
Well, Sissy?
Will it take long?
I'm ready.
Superintendent,
I only have one shell.
But orders are orders.
So be it.
It'll work.
Move over.
Let's see.
ASTAKHOV:
I see the target.
The tank turret. Lower left corner.
I think I got the angle right.
So?
Fire?
POLYAKOV:
Maybe God kissed you on the head?
U?“
CHVANOV:
Hell yes!
In Stalingrad,
even broken tanks
shoot! Ha-ha-ha!
NARRATOR:
Serge y Astakhov studied
at the artillery academy
in his hometown, Podolsk.
Just over a year ago,
in October, '41,
he and the other cadets
were called up
to defend the town
of Maloyaroslavets.
He was the only one
from his unit to survive.
Nobody then would have
called him a sissy.
But he was, in fact,
shy with girls.
COLONEL:
Kahn!
Are you out of
your mind?
They shot at us
from that building!
You didn't report artillery there.
You got snared by
a Russian whore and failed us.
Where were you?
Answer me!
I'm going to shoot
that whore.
She turned my best officer
into a mindless idiot.
And you, I'll have you shot too.
Fine.
But first I'm going to
take that building.
She'll wait here.
Kahn, if you don't take
the building,
I'll have you executed.
I know...
colonel.
U?“
NARRATOR:
All the people
my mother had known
and loved her whole life,
all her friends, neighbors and family,
had been killed
right before her eyes.
How she could bear this,
how she survived,
I can't tell you.
She rarely spoke of
the first months of the war.
She often told me stories
about peacetime life in the building.
I imagined all its inhabitants.
I knew that Misha Sazonov
was her neighbor,
that Mitya and Lena Kulikov
were her friends from downstairs,
that Auntie Khasil
gave her music lessons.
They had all been killed
in the August bombing raids.
The neighbors buried them
under some ruins
since the cemetery
was too far away.
The last graves appeared
after the Germans took the building.
Nikiforov. Let me go,
come on.
I need to go.
I'm looking for a present.
For Katya.
A birthday present. Okay?
Mama dug the graves herself
with her last ounce of strength.
Fourteen people,
adults and children,
lay in shallow graves
covered with stones.
Mama buried her sister and mother,
my aunt and grandma,
on the end so she wouldn't forget
where they were.
[WHISPERING]
It's here somewhere.
There it is.
A shell hit their plumbing.
They have no water,
no bath.
I bet she's been washing
with a rag for six months
and with cold water.
She'll be happy.
Krasnov.
MAN [IN GERMAN]:
What was her name? Olga?
Olga from the Volga.
[MEN LAUGH]
MAN:
They're all called Olga
or Natasha here.
[MEN LAUGHING AND CHATTERING]
[WHISPERS IN GERMAN]
Shut up.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Sergeant Scheumann, captain.
What can I do?
Do you have cigarettes?
Yes, sir.
Otto, the cigarettes.
What's broken?
Everything.
And the cannon?
Also broken.
It's the firing pin.
Why don't you fix it?
We don't have parts.
Supply is down.
I don't care if the tank runs.
I need the cannon.
Fix it or you'll attack on foot.
That's all.
Crawl? The hell with that.
Russian sailors don't crawl
like lizards.
Astakhov, there's a beat-up tank
over there.
Want to give that to Katya
as a present? Huh?
Okay. First torpedo,
stand by.
Second torpedo,
Fire.
U?“
They're up to something.
MAN [IN GERMAN]:
Attention!
Eyes straight ahead!
Are you the reinforcements?
Yes, sir.
What does your belt buckle say?
Spit it out!
"God with us."
Wherever God is,
our fuhrer, Adolf Hitler, is.
And wherever Hitler is,
all of Germany is.
Germany is here with us
right here.
I ask you,
what more do you need
to take down this damn building?
I'm listening!
ALL: Nothing, captain!
Beyond this building is the Volga.
Beyond this building
is the end of the war.
Beyond this building is India.
In India, all of the whores
have six arms.
Think of what those six hands
can all do at the same time.
Is there anyone
not keen to go to India?
You have 15 minutes.
Then we attack.
MAN:
Attention!
Sissy, get upstairs.
Go on, I said.
Katya, go with them.
Yell if anything happens.
Angel, get out of here.
Chvanov, Nikiforov,
take the corners.
I'll take the middle.
Come on. Let's go. Faster.
Everybody to that side.
Right side, that way. Spread out.
Come on, Fritz, over here!
Faster. Faster. Faster.
Let's go. Let's go.
Come on.
U?“
So they shoot, they come in
and then we cut them up.
Take cover.
MAN [IN GERMAN]:
No survivors down here.
Check the upper floors.
Aah!
Where are you going?
Freeze!
Not so fast,
captain.
Bad timing, Chvanov.
COLONEL:
Do you know what you are, Kahn?
You are a disgrace
to the entire Wehrmacht!
I'm going to headquarters now.
So you have some time.
I hope you'll use that time
wisely, captain.
What? Captain.
We've fixed the cannon.
Shot dead.
Didn't feel any pain.
That one, either.
Where's Katya?
In her room.
I'm gonna go dig the graves.
[FLOORBOARD CREAKING]
No, I won't go!
I'm not going anywhere!
[CANNON FIRES]
Fire!
What's wrong?
Why don't you fire?
The mechanism is stuck,
captain.
It's stuck again.
Shit!
U?“
NARRATOR".
Captain Gromov was
a professional hero. Wherever
there was war,
he was there.
Guangzhou, Khalkhin Gol,
the Mannerheim Line.
He had no loved ones,
no family,
no place he wanted
to go back to.
He'd been wounded three times.
Once almost fatally.
You're bleeding.
Where?
You have a shard.
Glass.
[SPITS]
Listen, get out of here.
Just leave.
You hear me?
I'm begging you.
Well?
I can't hear you.
I'm not going anywhere.
NARRATOR".
Mama's home was the first one
he'd ever felt attached to.
And Mama was the only woman
he had ever cared about for so long.
GROMOV:
Why did you come to me?
For what sins?
Why do I deserve you?
U?“
KAHN:
Will I ever again sit this peacefully
with a woman...
stroking her hair?
I don't understand you, Petya.
In Russian, you're Pyotr.
Petya for short.
Petya.
Not Petya.
Everything sounds funny
in Russian.
Masha...
Petya, Volga, whatever.
Love. Do you know
what that means?
I love you.
Love.
[IN GERMAN]
Love, love.
[IN RUSSIAN]
Your people would love
to shoot me,
and mine would love it more.
I don't care anymore.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
[MASHA SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
[IN RUSSIAN]
I don't care.
[BOTH SPEAK IN RUSSIAN]
[IN GERMAN]
I love you.
Move aside.
A little gift.
Thank you.
Smell it.
[SNIFFS]
Bliss.
Blow it out.
Well, shall we drink?
POLYAKOV: Happy birthday.
CHVANOV: Happy birthday.
Happy birthday.
Ooh.
Help yourselves.
Heh,heh,heh.
Ah, the main attraction.
Alexander Nikiforov
will sing love songs
and arias.
To the piano.
[ALL LAUGH]
[PIANO PLAYING AND
NIKIFOROV SINGING OPERA]
What am I supposed
to do?
[PIANO PLAYING AND
NIKIFOROV SINGING IN DISTANCE]
What do I do?
Tell me, German.
Damned war!
Damned country!
Damned building!
KATYA:
Thanks, Sasha.
ASTAKHOV:
Now a gift from all of us. Come on.
U?“
Ahem. Heroes,
the women's section
is now open.
Let's go downstairs.
[CHVANOV
CLEARS THROAT]
Let me see.
He's carried that tie
since the war started.
Heh, heh. Funny.
There's a naked girl,
but we can't look.
And we might die today.
You know what they say,
there's no life beyond
the Volga.
Angel, any left?
Okay, warriors.
Sleep.
Hurry up. Get dressed.
I'm taking
that building tomorrow,
whatever the cost.
We have to get you
to safety.
Nearby is a fire station
with a tower.
Nobody goes up there.
Not us, not the Russians.
I'll hide you there.
For one day.
One day.
Sergey. Don't go.
I'm so haPPY---
I'm scared.
Scared because
you're happy?
Yes.
I shouldn't be happy.
It's a war.
Katya, get dressed.
Please, get dressed.
I need to show you something.
It's not far.
The commander said it's okay.
KATYA:
Sergey.
Where are you taking me?
ASTAKHOV:
Just a minute.
Sit down.
It'll start now.
Look.
This was my lookout point.
Then the Germans found it.
They started shelling us.
We decided to redeploy.
Rem?
To move.
Oh.
They caught us downstairs.
Stay behind me.
Bitch.
Why are there
no Germans here?
Isn't it strange?
They're everywhere,
but not here.
That's true.
It is strange.
I hadn't thought about it.
Must be the only building
in the city like that.
No Germans
and no Russians.
That's good.
We'll wait it out here.
Wait out what?
Wait out the fear...
wait out the night...
wait out the terror.
The war.
We'll wait out everything.
Like we're on a cloud.
Katya.
I love you.
I've loved you
for two days now.
I know.
[WHISPERING]
Come.
Here.
You're staying here.
You're not going
anywhere.
I'll be back.
Pew!
Nikiforov.
Where's Katya?
Where's Astakhov?
Find them.
Wait.
What is it?
You'll come back?
Go back. Go back.
Kraut whore.
Russian!
MAN 1 [IN GERMAN]:
Colonel. We got a Russian scout.
Where did you find him?
Kahn found him
by the fire station.
He'd killed four
of our snipers.
Captain Kahn?
Bravo.
MAN 2 [IN GERMAN]:
What do we do with this scum?
Kahn, what should
we do with him?
Interrogate him.
COLONEL:
interrogate him?
How?
You speak Russian?
[IN GERMAN]
I speak German.
Get up, gramps.
Don't just sit there.
Tell your mutts
to give me food and water.
Why are you just
standing there?
I'm a Russian officer
on his knees,
you animals.
Where did you come from?
From that building
or the other bank?
I have a present for you.
What?
[IN RUSSIAN]
From a Russian girl.
Speak German.
Katya.
How strange.
I feel nothing.
Nothing.
No pain or anything.
But it itches under my arms.
The least these damn lice
could do is let you die in peace.
U?“
[IN GERMAN]
Lieutenant Schmidt, reporting.
Captain Kahn.
You got any cigarettes?
I'm driving
to the crossing the Russians
are building over the Volga.
Do you see that building?
See those two top floor windows?
I see them.
The Russian I want
has his headquarters there.
Will the cannon reach?
It's right in the line of fire.
Then do it.
What's that?
ASTAKHOV: Nothing.
Just some noise.
Come on, go to sleep.
It's early.
I need to go home.
I fell in love with you
right away,
at first sight.
I saw you and knew I loved you.
I love you too.
Really?
Really.
I'm going now.
I have to.
I'm going too.
No.
Wait for me here. Understand?
All right.
It's all over now!
Are you alive?
Yeah. What about you?
[IN STRAINED VOICE]
I'm okay.
You go ahead.
I'll wait for Nikiforov.
Go on.
KRASNOV:
We're going to die...
in an orchestra pit.
So, Angel,
time to go to heaven?
Heh, heh.
Why just to heaven?
I'm going to paradise.
I have a pass.
Heh,heh,heh.
KAHN: You're not the one.
Where is the other guy?
Where is the other
Russian?
KAHN:
Russian!
Russki!
HQ, come in, damn it.
HQ.
This is Gromov.
Get up.
Sissy, don't shoot.
The radio.
Do it.
ASTAKHOV:
HQ. HQ.
HQ.
MAN [ON RADICTLIIII-Jljg-I read you.
Give us an air-strike, now.
Coordinates:
24, 17, 14.
Do you read me?
MAN".
Kaluga. I didn't read you.
That's the building where our men are.
Is that right?
Mm-hm.
Yes, that's us!
The Germans are coming in!
Send an air-strike now!
I hear you, Kaluga. I hear you.
Goodbye, boys.
That's it.
Won't be long now.
GROMOV:
Wondering
about Katya?
She's fine. I hid her away.
She told me to say hello.
U?“
She also said...
she loves you very much.
U?“
NARRATOR".
It was in Stalingrad,
November, 1942.
Still to come
were months of bloody fighting
that would turn the tide
of human history
and the history of my great country.
Mama wanted me always
to remember the people
to whom millions upon millions
owe their lives and freedom.
And though she named me
after my father, Serge y,
she always said
I had five fathers.
Downstairs.
And he talked to us.
They had Sergey. Where is he?
He talked with me.
Astakhov's there.
Sergey.
Over there.
NARRATOR:
Mama also said
I'm lucky,
since I take after all of them.
And also because,
thanks to my fathers
and the fathers of my countrymen,
I have no idea what war is.
Stalingrad